{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "What recent development in cancer treatment involves modifying a patient's own T cells to attack cancer cells?",
        "options": [
          "Chemotherapy",
          "CAR T-cell therapy",
          "Radiotherapy",
          "Immunotherapy"
        ],
        "correct_answer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is a novel oral anticoagulant (NOAC) introduced in the last 20 years?",
        "options": [
          "Warfarin",
          "Heparin",
          "Rivaroxaban",
          "Aspirin"
        ],
        "correct_answer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "In the context of HIV treatment, what does the term 'PrEP' stand for?",
        "options": [
          "Post-exposure Prophylaxis",
          "Pre-exposure Prophylaxis",
          "Primary Resistance Elimination Protocol",
          "Progressive Replication Elimination Process"
        ],
        "correct_answer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these is a target of modern monoclonal antibody therapy in autoimmune diseases?",
        "options": [
          "TNF-Alpha",
          "Insulin",
          "Hemoglobin",
          "Amylase"
        ],
        "correct_answer": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "CRISPR-Cas9 technology, a significant recent development in genetic engineering, is primarily used for:",
        "options": [
          "Enhancing muscular strength in athletes",
          "Editing genes at specific locations",
          "Increasing the shelf life of perishable goods",
          "Developing new antibiotics"
        ],
        "correct_answer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the primary mechanism of action of the drug class known as SGLT2 inhibitors, used in diabetes management?",
        "options": [
          "Increasing insulin secretion",
          "Reducing glucose reabsorption in the kidneys",
          "Decreasing insulin resistance",
          "Enhancing glucagon secretion"
        ],
        "correct_answer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": " In the field of neurodegenerative diseases, which protein is primarily implicated in the pathogenesis of Alzheimer's Disease?",
        "options": [
          "Alpha-synuclein",
          "Beta-amyloid",
          "Myelin basic protein",
          "Huntingtin"
        ],
        "correct_answer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "The introduction of PCSK9 inhibitors is a significant advancement in the treatment of:",
        "options": [
          "Hypertension",
          "Hypercholesterolemia",
          "Type 2 Diabetes",
          "Chronic Kidney Disease"
        ],
        "correct_answer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the role of PD-1 inhibitors in cancer immunotherapy?",
        "options": [
          "They stimulate the production of white blood cells.",
          "They promote angiogenesis in tumor cells.",
          "They block a protein that prevents T cells from attacking cancer cells.",
          "They decrease the metabolic rate of cancer cells."
        ],
        "correct_answer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Biologic DMARDs, or Disease-Modifying Antirheumatic Drugs, used in rheumatology primarily act by:",
        "options": [
          "Inhibiting cyclooxygenase enzymes",
          "Stimulating cartilage growth",
          "They block a protein that prevents T cells from attacking cancer cells.",
          "Increasing calcium absorption in bones"
        ],
        "correct_answer": 3
      }
    ]
  }
  